Alex Ball

81 College Ave Apt. 2, Somerville, MA 02144 • (847) 650-2884 • ball.alex.509@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/alex-j-ball • github.com/alexjball • Open to opportunities: **no**

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full-stack applications, novel user experiences, complex problems, simple solutions

Experience designing and building in all layers of the stack: embedded devices, mobile clients, frontend servers, and backend servers.

Experience leading engineering in an Agile environment in collaboration with PM/UX/external stakeholders.

My core values: being mission-driven, attention to detail, organization, mutual respect and honesty, a high quality bar, and a focus on results. Most importantly, software should help people. I am excited to work with teams that share these values.

TECHNOLOGIES

Preferred: Modern Javascript, Node, CI/CD, C++. Also: Java, Python, C, Android, Matlab

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Cantina Consulting, Boston, MA. Senior Front-End Engineer

January 2020 - Present

Verily Life Sciences, Cambridge, MA. Software Engineer

October 2018 - June 2019

Feature developer for Onduo, a Type-II diabetes management app. Responsible for requirements gathering, design, and full-stack implementation.

Google, Cambridge, MA. *Software Engineer*

June 2016 - October 2018

Developed voice search and Google Assistant functionality for Wear OS, an Android-based smartwatch. Responsible for the integration between the Assistant and system UI.

HST Solar, Remote to Los Angeles, CA. *Software Engineer*

July 2015 - March 2016

Modeled ROI of utility-scale solar power plants. Created innovative plant layout optimization techniques using mixed integer linear programming. Provided high-level feasibility analyses to founders and demonstrated software for clients.

PROJECTS (See Github)

Share Space (React, Node, Vagrant, Linux sysadmin)

September 2019 - Present

Remote collaboration tool for sharing a virtual desktop between users. Users can view a low-latency video stream of the desktop and pass remote control between each other.

Migrant Service Map (Volunteer with Code for Boston) (Mapbox, React, Redux)

June 2019 - Present Allows social workers to easily locate and share information about immigration and refugee services.

Python Audio Lab

June 201

Library for live, interactive audio graph processing in Jupyter notebooks. Includes a notebook to perform live measurements of electric guitar pickup frequency response.

Video Feedback Simulation (Javascript, Three.js, WebGL)

March 2016 - 2017

Generative art. Users can intuitively manipulate fractals, generate extremely high resolution renderings, or set the simulation to run by itself.

EDUCATION

California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, CA BS, Major Physics, Minor Computer Science, Honors

June 2015

GPA: 3.8 / 4.0